<?xml version="1.0" encoding ="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Laughing My Way Forward</title>
    <description>Making a better life, better late than never</description>
    <link>https://www.laughingmywayforward.com/feed</link>
    <link href="https://www.laughingmywayforward.com/feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" />
    <item>
      <title>Fail Me Once, Shame On You</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What do you do when the person who scheduled your phone interview doesn't call you &lt;em&gt;for a second time&lt;/em&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, what I did after fifteen minutes was turn off my headset, resolve to ignore any calls, and applied for the same position at another franchise location.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What will I do if the person contacts me, apologizes, asks to try again? Probably tell the truth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;You didn't show up for two interviews. That tells me I shouldn't work with you, no matter what the reasons.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fail me twice, shame on you twice as much, and shame on me if I give you another chance.&lt;/em&gt; This is, after all, not a marriage or a child. It's a low-paying job to get my foot in the door and it's not the only door in town.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also applied to a different job teaching fitness classes for seniors. Since I'm a senior, that's probably a good fit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the home front, my wife and I played &lt;a href="https://bananagrams.com/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bananagrams&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; tonight. I told her and myself and the Cosmos that I didn't expect to win, I wouldn't win, and I didn't win. Her vocabulary and experience at words games is just too much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.laughingmywayforward.com/posts/fail_me_once__shame_on_you/2023-03-06-20-04-31.png" alt="" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's a good game, but not for us, not for now, not in the &amp;quot;it makes me laugh&amp;quot; kind of way I want to be playing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're still on the hunt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is my advice. Find a game you enjoy playing with your spouse who is also one of your best friends. Not a game you enjoy winning, but &lt;em&gt;playing&lt;/em&gt;. Whatever that means to both of you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 6 Mar 2023 19:51:09 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://www.laughingmywayforward.com/posts/fail_me_once__shame_on_you</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.laughingmywayforward.com/posts/fail_me_once__shame_on_you</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dochi? You Know It!</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This'll be a short entry. I didn't sleep so well last night, not due to depression but instead my belly aching--and not the slang kind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's a chronic thing I won't dwell on in this post. All was soothed when my wife took me out for &lt;a href="https://www.dochicompany.com/"&gt;dochi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/d/de/Seattle_in_January_2023_-_305.jpg" alt="" /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;sub&gt;Another Believer, CC BY-SA 4.0 &lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0"&gt;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0&lt;/a&gt;, via Wikimedia Commons&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She had salted caramel. I had a matcha and a cinnamon crunch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Was it world shattering, the microsecond man-made, more-energy-out-than-in &lt;a href="https://www.science.org/content/article/historic-explosion-long-sought-fusion-breakthrough"&gt;fusion reaction&lt;/a&gt; that proves the sun isn't the only cosmic energy game in town?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wouldn't go that far. It was an iced donut with a slightly chewy coating that was somehow satisfying. On the other hand, unlike nuclear fusion, I could hold it in my hand and feed bits to my wife. The latter drew an approving smile from the father of a family who were clearly there to pick up a big box of the things. At one point I wasn't sure if their filled box would survive the thirteen feet to the exit without being emptied. (More by parents than kids, I will not comment.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dochi were delightful. We didn't set out for downtown this morning in search of euphoria. Just a modicum of happy, a slice of grinny, a palate-pleasing, portmanteau pastry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It worked. And the iced Vietnamese coffee wasn't bad, either. Cảm ơn!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/b/ba/Vietnamese_Iced_Coffee.jpg" alt="" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 5 Mar 2023 18:54:05 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://www.laughingmywayforward.com/posts/dochi__you_know_it!</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.laughingmywayforward.com/posts/dochi__you_know_it!</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Don't Forget to Expect a Slingshot</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday was a bad day, last night was a very bad night, and this morning wasn't too swell, either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's one thing to give up a 30 year career and feel like the possibilities are endless. It's another to feel the pain of, essentially, the death of part of yourself. And then ya gotta expect that your wife might have her own feelings on the subject and that those feelings may not be all daffodils and triple ice cream banana splits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.laughingmywayforward.com/posts/don_t_forget_to_expect_a_slingshot/banana-split.png" alt="" /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;sub&gt;By Edward Allen Lim - &lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/kwein_01/3875309388/"&gt;https://www.flickr.com/photos/kwein_01/3875309388/&lt;/a&gt;, CC BY 2.0, &lt;a href="https://commons.wikimedia.org/w/index.php?curid=70288050"&gt;https://commons.wikimedia.org/w/index.php?curid=70288050&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This isn't a transcript of how the conversation went in reality. It is how it went in my heart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Are you disappointed in me?&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;For quitting your job without anything lined up, jeopardizing our retirement, pulling the rug out from under me, and surfacing a solid chunk of my childhood angst? 'Disappointed' might not be the ACT vocab word you're looking for.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;This isn't going to be a short talk, is it?&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;You might call that unlikely, slick.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The weather was cloudy, rainy, and cold. I'm one of those people whose emotions are lock-stepped to the weather like hormonal teens at a square dance. It's a big reason we moved to one of the sunniest states in the union. This is a real condition, my brain gets foggy, it's hard to concentrate, and the chances of depression in the forecast are in in the upper 80s. I was already, in a word, down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What destroyed me wasn't the talk. It was lying in bed, dwelling and reviewing and reliving and--finally--trying to think of any job in my life that a) I'd enjoyed and b) had not included a fight with management or open hostility with a coworker. I could think of two.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've had about twenty jobs. Which sounds absurd, but I was a contract software developer for over a decade so that meant several different clients. Before that: food service, retail, office work. I quit a lot of them, often because I had a tiff with management. I grew up thinking work was a place where you didn't get along with others, especially your bosses, who were likely idiots. It wasn't on purpose, it's just what my kid brain got taught.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, it's certainly not funny when you're lying there realizing the possibilities are certainly not endless, they are constrained by a terribly serious question: what job makes money and doesn't require me working with people?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(That's the extreme pessimistic, depressed version of the question. But you get the idea.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Software development &lt;em&gt;used&lt;/em&gt; to be that for me, because I was able to work somewhat independently. Then I bought a house, got married (second and final time) and decided I wanted stable employment. Seemed like a good idea at the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's some pretty good research showing that people's sense of well-being is strongly influenced by their sense of purpose. After a steadily worsening experience at my steady job, I announced to my wife that I wanted to find a workplace where I believed in the mission, enjoyed the culture, and wrote good code. How hard could that be to find? Almost ten years and three companies later, the answer was: not happening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why? Well, go back to my first post: about half of what I don't like in software engineering is inherent to the field. And I can't just &amp;quot;suck it up.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I broke. I lay in bed crying and heaving and my wife tried to comfort me at the same time I knew she was pissed which made me feel worse. Somehow I got to sleep. Somehow I got out of bed this morning, made my way to the local coffee shop, journaled (as the cool kids call it these days) for a couple of hours, then somehow came home to have another long talk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, it was a sunny morning, my wife was seeking understanding, we both brought our hard-learned marriage therapy skills&lt;a id="fnref:1" href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref"&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to bear, leading to an emotionally exhausting and loving resolution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We even resolved that it was OK for me to regularly tell her corny jokes. Like this one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.laughingmywayforward.com/posts/don_t_forget_to_expect_a_slingshot/wifi-corny-joke.png" alt="" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rest of the day has gone well. I got out and spent some time with friends, playing the French game &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/P%C3%A9tanque"&gt;Pétanque&lt;/a&gt;. My wife and I grocery shopped together. Our dog checked in with us to make sure everything was back to normal and that we'd still both be feeding him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a bad day, and a bad night, and a bad morning. But now it's OK. And that's what I need to remember.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="footnotes"&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:1"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.gottman.com/"&gt;Gottman&lt;/a&gt;-based research and techniques. I highly recommend this. It's solid science and has a clinically demonstrated high success rate.&lt;a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-back-ref"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 4 Mar 2023 20:16:20 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://www.laughingmywayforward.com/posts/don_t_forget_to_expect_a_slingshot</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.laughingmywayforward.com/posts/don_t_forget_to_expect_a_slingshot</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What I Don't Control</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I applied for a job and got scheduled for an interview within an hour. Today I was supposed to have that interview. It got rescheduled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where's the humor in that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.laughingmywayforward.com/posts/what_i_don_t_control/ludovic-migneault-B9YbNbaemMI-unsplash.jpg" alt="" /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;sub&gt;Photo by &lt;a href="https://unsplash.com/@dargonesti?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText"&gt;Ludovic Migneault&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href="https://unsplash.com/photos/B9YbNbaemMI?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText"&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the time there wasn't much. It was kind of deflating. Definitely fed the depression cloud. The interviewer didn't let me know. I contacted &lt;em&gt;her&lt;/em&gt; when she was ten minutes late. Not a great impression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But you know what? I have no idea what was happening in her day. Sure, it could be she'd had a bad day with no coffee, or has CUFV&lt;a id="fnref:1" href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref"&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or, it could be far, far worse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She may have come under siege by Phantom Mole Men.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unknown to most of you out there, Phantom Mole Men are a real problem, an insidious plague in the lives of those who cross their paths. These creatures, barely human, invisible to the eye&lt;a id="fnref:2" href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref"&gt;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, prey on folks--this could be you!--who sprinkle licorice Jimmies on chocolate ice cream, or prepare their taxes in early February, or carry a compact umbrella &lt;em&gt;just because&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Superman faced them. You can see surprisingly well-lit live news footage of those encounters if you &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QygK8gYl-2M"&gt;know where to look&lt;/a&gt;. Everyone who wore gray-scale clothes thought we'd seen the last of the fiends, but they hadn't disappeared. They'd merely vanished! Probably through the power of sub-terrestrial science, which my eighth grade teacher Mrs Glanderspoot warned me about when I kept hiding earthworms in Marla Flitkin's lunch bag.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But if they can't be seen (except as indicated in the footnotes. Hi, Aunt F.!), how do I know they exist at all? Because, they hide in plain sight. Here is a recent photograph of one of those infernals, masquerading as a common citizen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/4/40/Amadeo_Avogadro.png" alt="" /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;sub&gt;The original uploader was Anton at German Wikipedia., Public domain, via Wikimedia Commons&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you see this nondescript gent attempting to blend into a crowd, run! Escape with your life!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The PMMs are real, my friends. Fortunately they only harass their victims for a maximum of two hours and twenty seven minutes at a time every three years. No one knows why, but some day, with your financial help, we may find out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is why I'm not too concerned about having a successful rescheduled interview. My job seekee won't be afflicted, and neither will I because I'm buying a gila monster tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="footnotes"&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:1"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Calendar Use Fuggetaboutit Syndrome&lt;a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-back-ref"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:2"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, the &lt;em&gt;human&lt;/em&gt; eye. Bats can see them. So can gila monsters and my Aunt Francesca's mutant betta that's been swimming in the same aquarium since 1987. She says its long life is due to the vibrations of Prince--Aunt F's favorite--singing &lt;em&gt;Purple Rain&lt;/em&gt; every day.&lt;a href="#fnref:2" class="footnote-back-ref"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 3 Mar 2023 15:23:16 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://www.laughingmywayforward.com/posts/what_i_don_t_control</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.laughingmywayforward.com/posts/what_i_don_t_control</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Laughing My Way Forward</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I not only left my job, I left my career of almost 30 years. Maybe not permanently; that remains to be seen. But what do you think? My resignation email went something like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main reason I'm leaving is that I don't like this profession anymore. I dread starting my day, and my wife dreads hearing me talk about my job. That feeling has grown over the years and it's become too strong to ignore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a lot of interests, among them the science of well-being. I love the smartphone app &lt;a href="https://centerhealthyminds.org/join-the-movement/healthy-minds-app-provides-relief-from-pandemic-stress"&gt;Healthy Minds&lt;/a&gt;. It's a terrific, comprehensive program of evidence-based practices. There's an additional series of lessons, &lt;em&gt;Dalai Lama's Guide to Happiness&lt;/em&gt;. I've held off on this particular series because I'm a science guy, not a religion guy, and yes I know the position that Buddhism is a philosophy, and I'm not arguing that one way or the other. And the reason the Dalai Lama's featured in the app at all is that he's worked directly with Dr Richard Davidson, a world-renowned neuroscientist at the University of Wisconsin-Madison, to help understand what makes people happy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, science.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What matters is that in the very first lesson, when His Holiness is introduced, he's laughing. Here's a picture. He's the dude on the right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/b/bc/Dalai_Lama_with_Marco_Pannella.jpg" alt="" /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;sub&gt;(Mihai Romanciuc), CC BY-SA 2.0 &lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.0"&gt;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.0&lt;/a&gt;, via Wikimedia Commons&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This really struck me. You see, I suffer from chronic depression. It's--clinically speaking--mild most of the time, but has become worse over the last several years, impacting my job and marriage. You might think I grew up in a dour family full of strict protocols and cobwebby, dank conversations. But I didn't. My relatives love to laugh. I had a reasonably normal childhood and early adulthood, except for the part where I was surrounded by brilliant artists and super-smart minds. (Well, that was normal to &lt;em&gt;me&lt;/em&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depression does have an environmental component; our surroundings affect our thinking. Yet it's the brain's chemistry that leans some toward Mt Doom. As my therapist put it, we depressed folks have an ever-present gray cloud near us. That will never go away. What we control is whether we feed the cloud or starve it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.laughingmywayforward.com/posts/laughing_my_way_forward/grayclouds.png" alt="" /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;sub&gt;&lt;a href="https://unsplash.com/photos/weRtrhhTz4s"&gt;Harshit Sharma on Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's a great exercise that my wife had me do. It doesn't have to take long.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write down the things about your job you like and don't like.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Indicate which things are inherent to the job.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This only took me about fifteen minutes. In my case, I discovered that half of what I didn't like was also inherent to the job and the field. I told my wife I &lt;em&gt;used&lt;/em&gt; to like those parts of the job, but not anymore. That's when my situation clicked for her and me. Of &lt;em&gt;course&lt;/em&gt; I was unhappy. I was doing things I couldn't enjoy and weren't going to go away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Am I recommending dropping whatever you're doing and following your bliss? No, at least not on a whim. Be responsible. Be thoughtful. Don't trade one set of suffering for another unless it's a good trade. My situation isn't yours. I have conditional support from my wife of the &amp;quot;OK, I trust you, I want you to be happy and you haven't been which isn't fun for me or why I married you, but you can't be unemployed for long and we do have a nice house, a dog to feed, and retirement to think of&amp;quot; kind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I learned today is I need to get back to laughing and doing fun things with people. Life isn't all Gummi Bears and puppy piles. My storm cloud is ever-demanding to be fed. But some good belly-rockers are just the way to starve it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/3/3a/1981_People_Pix.jpg" alt="" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt;The original uploader was Mombas at English Wikipedia., CC BY 2.5 &lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.5"&gt;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.5&lt;/a&gt;, via Wikimedia Commons&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 2 Mar 2023 16:25:14 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://www.laughingmywayforward.com/posts/laughing_my_way_forward</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.laughingmywayforward.com/posts/laughing_my_way_forward</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>